# Dr. Martha Kalisz

mskalisz3@gmail.com | 847-814-3212 | Portsmouth, NH

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Highly motivated agile developer with strong skills in communication, observation, compromise, and teamwork. Keen interest and relative experience in problem solving and object-oriented programming. A compassionate professional skilled at establishing and maintaining rapport for effective systematic problem solving and troubleshooting. Flexible learner skilled in adapting to novel situations.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of North Carolina School of Medicine: Doctor of Physical Therapy - Chapel Hill, NC 2015-2018 University of Wisconsin School of Education: Bachelor of Science - Madison, WI 2011-2015 University of Minnesota's Learning Abroad Center: Fundación Ortega y Gasset - Toledo, ES Fall 2013

- International studies experience. Physical therapy intern, cultivated relationships, advanced Spanish language skills, created a blog.

## PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Pluralsight October 2021 - Present

Self-guided study in Agile Fundamentals, Scaling Agile, Intro to XP and Scrum, Kanban Fundamentals, Jira Overview.

**Launch School Core Curriculum** 

Self-guided study with heavy focus on computer science fundamentals. Courses completed include study of Object-Oriented Programming with Ruby, including debugging tools such as Rubocop, Git Fundamentals, and working with Regular Expressions. Focus on algorithm approach and problem solving. Courses in progress include study of JavaScript, HTML, CSS, HTTP, SQL, Web APIs, and Agile Planning. Designed, refactored, debugged small projects and games with basic coding design.

### **Udacity Front-End Nanodegree**

Nov 2020 - February 2021

February 2021 – Present

Self-guided study focusing on front-end software engineering. Courses included study of HTML, CSS, Flexbox, CSS grid, the Document Object Model, Git. Culminated in designing, creating, testing, and deploying four web-based projects with responsive layouts. Basics of asynchronous JavaScript, handing HTTP requests, Web APIs, Node, Webpack, and Sass.

## **TECHNICAL TOOLS**

Ruby, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git, GitHub, Node.js, Webpack, SASS, Visual Studio, Microsoft Office, Google Apps, and more

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Exeter Hospital Pediatric Rehabilitation, Epping NH**

September 2019 – Present

- Managed pediatric patients with variable and multidisciplinary needs on a large interdisciplinary pediatric team, requiring excellent teamwork and communication. Navigated COVID 19 pandemic, requiring constant flexibility and troubleshooting in planning. Mentored children and young adults. Advocated for mentorship. Navigated Meditech systems.

#### Elliot Hospital Rehabilitation, Londonderry NH

November 2018 - 2019

- Managed patients with diverse diagnoses while working closely with MDs and PAs in order to coordinate patient care per protocol. Supervised PT aides, students. Advocated for mentorship. Navigated Epic systems.

## Clinical Clerkship, Various Cities NC

Summers 2016 - 2018

- Four, 8 to 12-week clinical rotations involving on the job learning in various clinic settings. Learned to navigate different electronic medical systems in each. Collaborated with hospital physicians and staff to coordinate care plans demonstrating excellent communication. Provided novel knowledge to peers and mentors via in-services.

## Office Assistant, University of North Carolina Chapel Hill Division of Physical Therapy

Summer 2016-Spring 2018

- Assisted with research and office tasks while studying to obtain a doctorate degree; operated, gathered data, organized UNC's Stroke Research Registry. Facilitated clinic organization including insurance, chart management, and patient scheduling via in-person, phone, and email contacts.

## Campus Visit Specialist, Campus and Visitor Relations, Madison, WI

Summer 2013-2015

- Managed multiple accounts and collaborated with Campus Partners to plan specialty visits and tours for approx. 30,000 guests per year while pursuing a Bachelor's degree.

## Research Assistant, Dr. Eldridge's Pediatric Cardiopulmonary Lab, UW Hospital, Madison, WI

Summer 2014-Spring 2015

- Contributed to the execution of translational studies and data analysis handling bronchopulmonary dysplasia and right ventricle interactions.

## LICENSURE AND CERTIFICATION

Licensed Physical Therapist - New Hampshire **CPR/AED for the Professional Rescuer** 

October 2018 - Present September 2021